<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--This file is part of Chummer5a.

    Chummer5a is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
    (at your option) any later version.

    Chummer5a is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU General Public License for more details.

    You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
    along with Chummer5a.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses />.

    You can obtain the full source code for Chummer5a at
    https://github.com/chummer5a/chummer5a
-->
<chummer>
  <qualities>
    <!--
      Altered Positive
    -->
    <quality>
      <name>Alibi</name>
      <bonus amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <specificskill>
          <name>Con</name>
          <bonus>2</bonus>
        </specificskill>
      </bonus>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Biocompatibility (Cyberware)</name>
      <chargenonly />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Biocompatibility (Bioware)</name>
      <chargenonly />
    </quality>
    <quality xpathfilter="name = 'Fractal Punch' or name = 'Hold the Door' or name = 'Lone Wolf' or name = 'Team Player' or name = 'Trust Data, Not Lore' or name = 'Trust Lore, Not Data' or name = 'Unique Avatar'">
      <required>
        <oneof xpathfilter="quality = 'Technomancer'" amendoperation="remove" />
      </required>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Null Wizard</name>
      <bonus>
        <skilldisable amendoperation="addnode">Summoning</skilldisable>
      </bonus>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Home Ground</name>
      <notes>
        - The selected benefit applies to an entire district of Seattle (Renton, Bellevue, Snohomish, etc.)
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>I C U</name>
      <notes>
        - Note that you need to have visual sight on the target in the physical world to get the bonus. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Master Debater</name>
      <notes>
        - This allows you to substitute logic for charisma in your negotiation rolls.
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Nasty Trog</name>
      <notes>
        - Keep in mind you're going to look pretty persona non grata in "polite" society as a result of making yourself look extra trog. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Fame: Megacorporate</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Otaku to Technomancer</name>
      <chargenonly />
      <notes>
        - To have the full flavor of a former Otaku it's also recommended to have a datajack and a character age roughly between 20 to 35 years old. However, this is not mandatory.
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Fame: Global</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Practice, Practice, Practice</name>
      <notes>
        - Any Hub contacts with the Aptitude quality can provide this quality for any of their skills
        - This quality only applies to Mental, Physical, and Social limits. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Privileged Family Name</name>
      <notes>
        - Remember: Mind magic is stringently discouraged on the 'Hub for thematic reasons, so note that the reactions of runners may be severe if discovered and attempting to use your name to get the cops to ignore mind magic usage is a no-go. Other types of magic usage without a license are fine under the text of the quality. 
      </notes> 
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Prototype Transhuman</name>      
      <chargenonly />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Redliner</name>
      <notes>
        - The strength and agility bonus applies to all of the character's cyberlimbs. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Restricted Gear</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit CCD approval and may be denied without further comment.
        - In general it is more likely to be approved when used for flavorful gear that ties well into a character's background, whereas attempts to simply use it to maximize a character's power are very likely to be denied.
        - Either way, CCD always has final say whether the quality may be used or not. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Strive For Perfection</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality applies to any weapon, including unarmed attacks.
        - The advantage halves the penalty for any called shot. When combined with other ways to reduce the penalty, the penalty is halved after the other reductions have been applied.
        - Keep in mind the drawback: You must make called shots unless you are using some other form of special attack (such as suppressing fire, multiple attacks, or nerve strike). This is not optional. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Corporate Loyalist</name>
      <required amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <oneof>
          <quality>SINner (Corporate)</quality>
          <quality>SINner (Corporate Limited)</quality>
        </oneof>
      </required>
    </quality>
    <!--
      Banned Positive Qualities
    -->
    <quality>
      <name>Better to be Feared Than Loved</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Community Connection</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Erased</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Friends in High Places</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Groveler</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Revels in Murder</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Trust Fund I</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Trust Fund II</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Trust Fund III</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Trust Fund IV</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <!--
      Changed Negative
    -->
    <quality>
      <name>Stay Out of My Way</name>
      <notes>In order to avoid needlessly antagonistic application, the composure test on this quality may not apply to other players. CCD has the right to deny this quality without further comment if they deem it necessary to do so.
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Thousand-Yard Stare</name>
      <notes>Due to concerns over potentially distasteful application, this quality may be denied by CCD without further comment.</notes>
    </quality>
    <quality xpathfilter="starts-with(name,'Corporate Pariah')">
      <required amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <oneof>          
          <quality>SINner (Corporate)</quality>
          <quality>SINner (Corporate Limited)</quality>
        </oneof>
      </required>
    </quality>
    <quality xpathfilter="name = 'On the Wagon'">
      <required>
        <oneof xpathfilter="quality = 'Technomancer'" amendoperation="remove" />
      </required>
    </quality>
    <quality xpathfilter="name = 'Wired User'">
      <required>
        <allof xpathfilter="quality = 'Technomancer'" amendoperation="remove" />
      </required>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Addiction (Mild)</name>
      <notes>
        - Addictions must be to a statted, 'Hub-legal drug. Addiction to activities and unrestricted items - gambling, alcohol, smoking, etc. - provides no mechanical benefit in the form of additional Karma.
        - Characters may, if desired by the player, have 0 Karma Addiction qualities to activities or unrestricted items for the sake of roleplaying. 
        - Addictions to simsense (cold- and hot-sim) as well as skillwires are not enforced on Runnerhub, and therefore aren't allowed as subjects for the addiction quality. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Addiction (Moderate)</name>
      <notes>
        - Addictions must be to a statted, 'Hub-legal drug. Addiction to activities and unrestricted items - gambling, alcohol, smoking, etc. - provides no mechanical benefit in the form of additional Karma.
        - Characters may, if desired by the player, have 0 Karma Addiction qualities to activities or unrestricted items for the sake of roleplaying. 
        - Addictions to simsense (cold- and hot-sim) as well as skillwires are not enforced on Runnerhub, and therefore aren't allowed as subjects for the addiction quality. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Addiction (Severe)</name>
      <notes>
        - Addictions must be to a statted, 'Hub-legal drug. Addiction to activities and unrestricted items - gambling, alcohol, smoking, etc. - provides no mechanical benefit in the form of additional Karma.
        - Characters may, if desired by the player, have 0 Karma Addiction qualities to activities or unrestricted items for the sake of roleplaying. 
        - Addictions to simsense (cold- and hot-sim) as well as skillwires are not enforced on Runnerhub, and therefore aren't allowed as subjects for the addiction quality. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Addiction (Burnout)</name>
      <notes>
        - Addictions must be to a statted, 'Hub-legal drug. Addiction to activities and unrestricted items - gambling, alcohol, smoking, etc. - provides no mechanical benefit in the form of additional Karma.
        - Characters may, if desired by the player, have 0 Karma Addiction qualities to activities or unrestricted items for the sake of roleplaying. 
        - Addictions to simsense (cold- and hot-sim) as well as skillwires are not enforced on Runnerhub, and therefore aren't allowed as subjects for the addiction quality. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Aged</name>
      <notes>
        - Elves and Dwarves live for hundreds of years, while Orks and Trolls live a fraction of the human lifespan. A character's age must be adjusted accordingly, and Elves and Dwarves may not be pre-Spike Baby ages. This means you cannot play an aged Dwarf or Elf. 
      </notes>
      <forbidden amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <oneof>
          <metatype>Elf</metatype>
          <metatype>Dwarf</metatype>
        </oneof>
      </forbidden>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Albinism I</name>
      <notes>
        - Albinism is not compatible with Distinctive Style. You may take a distinctive style for something other than being an Albino though. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Albinism II</name>
      <notes>
        - Albinism is not compatible with Distinctive Style. You may take a distinctive style for something other than being an Albino though. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Asthma</name>
      <notes>
        - Asthma is not compatible with Allergy: Pollutants, or similar cases. This is subject to sheet team approval. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Big Baby</name>
      <notes>
        - Subject to CCD approval per sheet.
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Code of Honor</name>
      <notes>
      - Custom codes of honor are not allowed at chargen. If you would like to take this quality in character creation, you must select from one of the already defined codes of honor in the books (Like a Boss, etc.) 
      Nationalist:
      - This quality is allowed for UCAS only.
      - CCD may deny characters with this quality submitted to r/hubchargen without comment.
      - It is strongly advised that characters with this quality also have the National SINner: UCAS quality. 
      Thug Life:
      - The expenses (half your income) are treated the same way as a SIN tax: they apply to your direct run rewards, and do not affect Working for the Man/People.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Code of Honor: Like a Boss</name>
      <notes>
      - The Code of Honor is also violated if a sprite or agent under the player’s control causes matrix damage to a target.
      - It doesn’t extend to physical actions that cause matrix damage (e.g. using electric attacks against drones).
      </notes>
    </quality>
    <quality>
      <name>Dead Emotion</name>
      <notes>
        - The chosen emotion requires explicit sheet team approval, and the player should work with the sheet team to figure out how it affects the character and then note it on the character’s sheet.
        - This quality doesn’t make a character immune to artificially induced emotions (e.g. through a critter’s Fear power) - it’s still a negative quality, after all.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Driven</name>
      <notes>
        - Whatever a character's driving force is, it has to have a specific end goal that must be realistically possible to work towards and achieve in play on the 'hub. Once this goal has been achieved, the quality has to be bought off immediately.
        - Whether any given goal fulfills these criteria is subject to the sheet team's discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Distinctive Style</name>
      <notes>
        - The character has 2 Public Awareness that can only be removed when buying off the quality.
        - If the character covers, removes, or otherwise hides what makes their style distinctive, they take a -1 penalty to all actions until they uncover/wear/show their style.
        - Characters who have this quality as a consequence of a metagenetic quality or from being a metavariant do not suffer the penalty when hiding their style and do not have the additional Public Awareness, and suffer only the RAW ramifications of this quality. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Frostbite</name>
      <bonus amendoperation="replace">
        <selectskill limittoskill="Computer, Cybercombat, Decompiling, Electronic Warfare, Hacking, Software"></selectskill>
      </bonus>
    </quality>
      
    <quality>
      <name>Incomplete Deprogramming</name>
      <notes>
        - On character submission the player needs to provide a description of the alternate identity. This is subject to sheet team approval. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infirm</name>
      <notes>
        - Buying off Infirm does not restore attributes that it lowered when the quality was acquired. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Lazy Fingers</name>
      <karma>-6</karma>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Pacifist II</name>
      <notes>
        - At the 15 karma level, you are unable to directly facilitate violence at all - including paying for violence to happen or helping someone else procure the means of committing violence.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Poor Self Control (Sadistic)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied without further comment. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Records on File</name>
      <notes>
        - On character submission the player needs to provide a list of the corporations that have the files, along with what specific information the corporation holds on the character and why they have those records.
        - This list should be adequately explained in the character's background section on their character sheet, and must be thematically appropriate to the background of the character. 
        - This quality is limited to 3 ranks (or 3 corporations) at character creation. 
      </notes>
      <limit>3</limit>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Reduced Sense (Hearing)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied if deemed not appropriate, as per sheet team discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Reduced Sense (Sight)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied if deemed not appropriate, as per sheet team discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Reduced Sense (Smell)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied if deemed not appropriate, as per sheet team discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Reduced Sense (Taste)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied if deemed not appropriate, as per sheet team discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Reduced Sense (Touch)</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied if deemed not appropriate, as per sheet team discretion. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Sloppy Code</name>
      <notes>
        - Applies to LOG+Sleaze tests and the Hide action.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Superhuman Psychosis</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality requires explicit sheet team approval and may be denied without further comment.
        - Characters with this quality won’t accept help or directions from anyone they consider inferior to themselves (i.e. everyone, even other people with the same affliction), and therefore cannot receive bonuses from leadership or teamwork tests.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Signature</name>
      <notes>
        - On character submission the player needs to provide a description of the signature. The signature must be uniquely used as a signature and cannot be an item or action that would be regularly used for another purpose (in combat, as a tool, etc). This quality is subject to sheet team approval. 
      </notes>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Wanted</name>
      <notes>
        - Not allowed to pick, but can be gotten as a run "reward"
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Spirit Bane</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality must be taken for a spirit within the character's magical tradition. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Trog Traitor</name>
      <notes>
        - Keep in mind that, per the Codified Missions Errata, characters with this quality take a negative modifier to their social limit equal to their notoriety.
        - Expect that what constitutes an ork- or troll-majority area to vary by GM.
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Unsteady Hands</name>
      <notes>
        - It is up to GM discretion whether it triggers at the beginning or end of combat. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Weak Immune System</name>
      <notes>
        - This quality applies its effect to Toxins as well as Diseases, increasing their effect by +2. 
      </notes>
    </quality>

    <!--
      Banned Negatives
    -->

    
    <quality>
      <name>Alpha Junkie</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Amnesia (Neural Deletion)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Bi-Polar</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Big Regret</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Borrowed Time</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Code of Honor: Avenging Angel</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Code of Honor: Black Hat</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Consummate Professional</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Data Liberator</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Day Job (10 hrs)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Day Job (20 hrs)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Day Job (40 hrs)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Designated Omega</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Earther</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Echo Chamber</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Elevated Stress</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Emotional Attachment</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Every Man For Himself</name>
      <hide/>
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Faceless</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Force of Chaos</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Hobo with a Shotgun</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Hung out to Dry</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Impassive</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>In Debt</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>Information Auctioneer</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Latest and Greatest</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Leeeeeeeroy Jenkins</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>One of Them</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Pie Iesu Domine. Dona Eis Requiem.</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Pregnant</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>This Is Your Last Chance</name>
      <hide/>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Tough and Targeted</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    
    <quality>
      <name>'Ware Intolerance</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <!--
      Changed/Banned Mastery
    -->
    <quality>
      <name>Astral Bouncer</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Barehanded Adept</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Chosen Follower</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Practiced Alchemist</name>
      <karma>10</karma>
    </quality>

    <!--
      Banned Infected Qualities
    -->
    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Bandersnatch</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Banshee</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Dzoo-Noo-Qua</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Fomoraig</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Gnawer</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Goblin</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Grendel</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Harvester</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Loup-Garou</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Mutaqua</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Nosferatu</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Vampire (Human)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Vampire (Non-Human)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Sukuyan (Human)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Sukuyan (Non-Human)</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Infected: Wendigo</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Wildcard Chimera</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>  

    <quality xpathfilter="starts-with(name, 'Carrier')">
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <!--
      Banned Crystals
    -->
    <quality xpathfilter="starts-with(name, 'Crystal')">
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <!--
      Banned Dracoforms
    -->
    <quality xpathfilter="starts-with(name, 'Draco')">
      <hide />
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <name>Latent Dracomorphosis</name>
      <hide />
    </quality>
    <!--
      Disallowing Class 1 & 2 changelings
    -->
      <quality>
        <name>Changeling (Class I SURGE)</name>
        <hide />
      </quality>

      <quality>
        <name>Changeling (Class II SURGE)</name>
        <hide />
      </quality>

    <!--
      Banned Dissonant Streams
    -->
      <quality>
        <name>Dissonant Stream: Apophenian</name>
        <hide />
      </quality>
      
      <quality>
        <name>Dissonant Stream: Erisian</name>
        <hide />
      </quality>
      
      <quality>
        <name>Dissonant Stream: Morphinae</name>
        <hide />
      </quality>
      
    <!--
      Overrides
    -->

    <quality>
      <id>9d53e1e4-3f31-40cb-bfbe-4b94f5ba757e</id>
      <name>Mystic Adept</name>
      <bonus>
        <unlockskills amendoperation="remove" />
        <unlockskills amendoperation="addnode">Sorcery</unlockskills>
        <unlockskills amendoperation="addnode">Conjuring</unlockskills>
      </bonus>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <id>45be40cc-a21a-4771-b47d-a532ea60b205</id>
      <name>Made Man</name>
      <bonus amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <mademan />
        <addcontact>
          <connection>4</connection>
          <loyalty>3</loyalty>
          <free />
        </addcontact>
      </bonus>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <id>7297d8b0-8bb8-4d7a-ab10-2d4e4381e5d0</id>
      <name>Prime Datahaven Membership</name>
      <bonus amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <addcontact>
          <connection>5</connection>
          <loyalty>3</loyalty>
          <free />
        </addcontact>
      </bonus>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <id>aaac8dfd-dee6-4277-b967-9ec9089260a7</id>
      <name>Cyber-snob</name>
      <karma>-6</karma>
      <bonus>
        <disablebiowaregrade xpathfilter="contains(., 'Alphaware')" amendoperation="remove" />
        <disablecyberwaregrade xpathfilter="contains(., 'Alphaware')" amendoperation="remove" />
      </bonus>
      <required>
        <oneof>
          <ess xpathfilter="@grade = 'Betaware'" amendoperation="replace" grade="Alphaware">1</ess>
        </oneof>
      </required>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <id>a030d7e2-755b-4f71-b848-ad9772fba242</id>
      <name>Distinctive Style</name>
      <bonus>
        <publicawareness>2</publicawareness>
      </bonus>
    </quality>

    <quality>
      <id>727e5ca7-0b64-462f-a3dc-254c451db3a1</id>
      <name>Pacifist Adept</name>
      <required>
        <oneof>
          <quality xpathfilter=". = 'Pacifist II'" amendoperation="remove" />
        </oneof>
      </required>
      <forbidden amendoperation="replace" addifnotfound="True">
        <oneof>
          <quality>Pacifist II</quality>
        </oneof>
      </forbidden>
    </quality>

    <!--
      Template:
      <quality>
        <name></name>
        <hide />
      </quality>

      <quality>
        <name></name>
        <notes>
        </notes>
      </quality>
    -->

  </qualities>
</chummer>
